[laughter]
>> I can't say anything.
I can't say anything.
I guess I followed your mock draft, I
guess.
It's all good. Uh
questions?
Yeah, we've we've been pretty we've been
pretty as
many questions as I fielded from you
guys about that position.
We've been pretty clear about, you know,
what the what the requirements are at
that position for us and and he he he
fits that. You know, he's a he's a
physical player that he he he can set
hard edges.
His pass rush greatly improved and
when I look at Derek, it's a much
similar like Blake Miller
that that we took yesterday in terms of
been watching him for a long time and
have always felt the length and the
physicality and the power in the past,
but
didn't really feel like his rush was
quite there yet, but this year he really
got better and then when he went down to
Mobile at the Senior Bowl, he he strung
together a really good week rushing the
passer. So,
he's another one that has a floor coming
in, but he's getting better and better
and better and just like I said with
Blake Miller, I don't see why that's
going to stop in this ecosystem. So,
really really excited cuz it's it's hard
to find guys that
you know, I'm not going to say we're
picky, but you know, we we just have a a
certain type that we like and and he
fits those boxes.
Cuz you brought up with with Tesla last
year at the Senior Bowl, right? That's
such a
kind of bang bang bang event, right?
There's three practices and a game like
what is it about that event where you
see a guy stand out there that that's
really a draw to you? Yeah, it's just
you just know that look in and credit to
the guys that put the game together, you
know, I mean it was it was Jim Nagy in
the past and you know, he passed the
torch to Drew Fab and I thought Drew Fab
did a really nice job putting together
that roster, but it's just seeing that
type of competition in in real raw
practices
for a whole week, you know, and then
playing the game and you can just it's a
lot of stories that you can get from it.
There's some smaller school
developmental guys they get to have
rough days at the start of the week and
they kind of get better and then have a
good games and you know, not everybody
plays in the game. There's some guys
that you know, a lot of guys opt out and
they play the whole game. I mean, I
think that that says a lot, but
Derek, I don't think he played in the
game, but his his practices were were
really really good, but I knew for him
what he showed was not only did he
really show that he was an improved pass
rusher, not just outside on the edge. He
can sub rush, too, which is very
intriguing about him as well. I think
that was very underrated component of
his game,
but
I I thought he did a nice job proving at
the Senior Bowl versus top competition
that he's a he's a real pass rusher.
Oh, I was going to say your first two
picks offensive tackle and edge rusher.
Is that just a perfect blend of what you
need, but also that what that was one of
the guys you wanted?
>> Yeah, no, it it really did line up just
cuz you know, like we've always said,
you know, we're we're going to take the
best player. So,
you know, look if if there was
I'm sure there was other tackles that
were available or there was other, you
know, edge rushers that were available,
but you know, but these were the guys
that we liked. So, you know, when it
when it when it blends together like
that, it's it's really nice, but
yeah, could couldn't be happier actually
just from today and yesterday. I know we
still got a lot of picks tomorrow or we
lost one pick when we traded up, but I
still feel like we got we got enough
ammo to still make a little bit of hay
tomorrow as well, but yeah, I just
I didn't feel like it was any kind of
reaching for positions or anything like
that. I know that those were the popular
positions and all that stuff that they
were talked about for us, but
they just happened to be players that we
really liked.
Just off that and really your first no
answer to Justin a little bit, too, but
can you explain your vision for the
defensive line and how Derek right like
what he can do on the edge to complete
that because you have been, you know,
picky and and people in this room have
been on you a little bit, but obviously
you're looking for something, you know,
to
>> [laughter]
>> Probably not.
>> [clears throat]
>> No,
it's a good question just because um
what what what what Derek is going to
bring, you know, to the defense is first
of all like
you know, like you said, you want to
call it just being very selective on the
type of guys that we get, you know,
you know, Hutch takes a lot of snaps,
man. You know, so just to have another
body that literally can spell Hutch in
that in that in that rush rotation.
You know, when you line up, you know, in
in nickel and sub defense, you know, a
guy that can line up on the opposite, a
guy that can line up inside.
You know, Shep just going to put the
guys in the best position to what they
do best and so
that's what he showed on tape is he can
set edge in the run game. He can rush
outside, he can rush inside and I'm
quite sure that's what how Shep's going
to utilize him.
Film it seemed like whenever the ball
carrier was in his vicinity, he's a
really good tackler in space.
Maybe not something that you think of as
like the primary skill set for an edge,
but what is it about what he does well
there and how valuable is that to you?
Yeah, well, you always say, you know,
you got to you got to get to third down.
You got to you know, you got to earn the
right to run the to rush the passer and
so
those are those the the the dirty work
he doesn't mind to do, but it's also a
testament to his instincts as well. And
so we start talking about guys that have
good floors or higher floors coming in,
you know, usually those guys are are
instinctive players and that's what he
is. He's very instinctive in the run
game and um
it just it matters cuz you just can't
just be just yeah, you know, we talk
about edge rusher rush rush rush. Well,
yeah, I mean, we want to get to the
quarterback, but you can't just get
gashed all the way down field either.
And so I think that's a good component
to his game he's going to bring.
How beneficial was it to see him
play in an NFL system? You know, they've
obviously they've had that Raven style
defense since Yeah.
Yeah, you know, yeah, I mean, it's it's
it's very beneficial. You know, it's
it's it's hard enough playing the
all the forecasting and projecting that
we have to do when we're evaluating
these prospects. So, when you see guys
coming out of these programs like a
Michigan or you know, like what we've
done in the past at you know, Alabama or
Iowa or you know, Georgia like those
those guys run NFL systems. So, you
know, all the way down to the alignment
and the assignment. So, to be able to
kind of take a little bit of weight off
your back in terms of from a projection
standpoint and now you can kind of hone
in on, you know, what kind of physical
and mental makeup they have for us, but
it but it definitely helps because a lot
of the things that Derek did it might
not be the exact same, but it's I'm sure
it's going to be a lot of carry over.
Guys like Blake and Derek where you said
they've improved a lot over the years.
Like what are you looking for to confirm
that they can keep growing?
Really just I would say their their
their work ethic and their football
character and you know, that's that's
all the work that all the scouts do
during during the year just vetting
sources and all of that. Now, they have
to have the they have to have the proper
gears in their body to actually be able
to ascend.
It kind of starts there, but there's a
lot of guys that have the gears in their
body, but they don't have the other
stuff. So, that's why we just put so
much work and stock into the into the
intangibles and the work ethic and all
of that. So, talking about Derek or
Blake like when a guy is coachable, you
know, he loves football. They both love
football and you know, and they're and
they're going to do everything in their
power to do to be a good football
player.
You have to make sure they're that first
and then okay, you start looking at the
other stuff. So, I do think they'll get
better.
When you trade up for Derek today, are
you worried someone's going to get him?
Was this the guy that you woke up this
morning, you know, having that
conviction to get? What what was that
like what goes on in your head
>> Yeah, well, I would say
he was one of the I would say he was
part of that cluster. He was part of
that cluster of guys that we were
targeting today. So, he was already at
at top of mind going up, but just kind
of paying attention to who was in front
of us, who was behind us.
You know, there was it felt like just
right in that area there was a multiple
edge rushers that were flying off. So,
and again, I I always say like that's
the fascination of the draft. You don't
know. So, you know,
Derek might have been, you know, our you
know, three or four edge rusher or
whatever whatever it is for, but he was
today he was our one
for for what what was available, but
other teams he could have been there
seven or eight and you you can't worry
about that. You just got to just get the
guy that you want.
You had to make sure you get got
somebody in that cluster.
>> Yes. Yes, that's that's exactly what
we're doing.
Yes. You guys you guys lost a lot of
production with Okafor
11 sacks. Yeah. Is it too much to ask a
rookie to
>> I'm glad you asked me a question,
Carlos.
That's what I'm here for. Well, I feel
like when you don't know, I feel like
>> [laughter]
>> I was just kind of Just just waiting in
the Just waiting. I'm like
Tiger in the tall grass. Good. Sorry.
Yeah, so just when you lose that kind of
production, is it unreasonable to expect
a rookie to come close to double digit
sacks? Do you expect that to come
elsewhere? What are your expectations
for him as a rookie? Yeah, look, he just
needs to come in and be who he is. You
know, that's that's not the reason why
we drafted him, Carlos, is that, you
know, like he has to replace
Clowney's production. And no, it's not
that. Like if he does, great, you know,
but that's that's not why we drafted
him.
We do expect that he can become that
player, you know, to meet that kind of
production
in time, but that's not why we we
drafted him. But I will say him coming
on board, he's going to add to, you
know, just the overall production of our
defense of just adding more sacks and
pressures getting to the quarterback.
How do you think that
DJ and Derrick Moore complement each
other? Like maybe slightly different
physical profile, stature. How do you
see those two guys, Wonnum and Derrick
Moore, complementing each other?
>> Yeah, I think they are good complements
cuz they're both physical players.
They're they're a little bit different,
you know, a little bit different body
types, but but I think they're both I
mean, again, that's why they're here is
that, you know, they fit the
requirements of what we look for at that
position. So, they both set good edges.
They they both can rush outside, they
both can rush inside. So, I'm quite sure
that, you know, and they're and they're
also both good teammates, too. So, I'm
I'm quite sure that, you know, you know,
DJ being the veteran, I'm sure that he's
going to help Derrick a lot, but but I
it's it's it's a good question because I
do think there are some some
similarities. You guys are big on
intangibles, too, obviously. What does
he have? Is it Is it similar to Miller
or different in the two guys that you
picked?
>> Yeah, well, first of all, it starts with
their passion for football, you know,
they they they both love football. You
know, they'll they're they're going to
do everything they got to do to make
sure that their body is right, that
they're in shape, that they're being
coachable, and that they're laying it
all out on the line. And,
you know, look, there's nobody that's
that's perfect or anything like that.
Everybody has mistakes, but
the passion for football is is numero
uno for us. And so, that that's where
they're very similar. They they both
love football.
>> [snorts]
>> Coaches' impact in your overall scouting
process. I know you bring them in kind
of towards the end of the process and
get their their opinions. So,
coach Rogers and and Shep, you know, how
how did they maybe help you land on this
player if at all? Yeah, they they
they're a huge help on the vision
aspect. And obviously, you know, they
they evaluate the the players, and you
know, we we have good meetings, we have
good dialogue,
cuz there's some guys that, you know, we
will will see differently. You know,
there's some guys that maybe that I
might like the football player, but, you
know, just not really sure where he's
going to fit, you know. So,
but I will say this, what what's been
cool about Shep is his his
open-mindedness in terms of that
if a guy has a skill set or a let's call
it a superpower,
he's he's not going to be rigid and say,
"Well, he doesn't fit in this box, so he
can't like this guy does this well, then
we're going to find a place for him to
to do that." So, but they're they're
very helpful their evaluations, their
experience, and then just also just
fitting that vision. Were you nervous
Baltimore was going to grab him
was going to grab him? Is that why you
had they were right after you guys, the
Ravens? You know, I don't know if they
wanted him or not, but you know, kind of
got a sense that they were in the edge
rusher market, though.
But just, you know, about us getting on
you a little bit about getting a
defensive end, was it
beyond, you know, I mean, I know,
getting him was most important, but just
to get a defensive end, is that nice to
get us off your back?
>> [laughter]
>> No, that that def was definitely an
afterthought after we after we picked
him, but I did think about it while
walking down. I was like, "Finally, I'm
going to the podium we drafted this man
I don't know what, 22 or something and
we did it." So,
but no,
again, look, we just,
you know, it just again, I can't say it
probably sound like a broken record.
It's not something that we have been
ignoring. It just it just just has to
line up. Like I've said, the years past,
year before, look, we could do these
things to draft a defensive end every
single round every single year. That
that's very easy to do.
But you want them to be a good player
and produce. Well, then now you're
dealing with something else, you know.
So,
that's that's that's what the hope is
for for Derrick, and you know, we feel
good about it. Do you think there's
maybe still an opportunity to
be active tonight? I mean, there's still
36, 37 picks.
>> We're probably done. I'm not going to
hide anything. I mean,
I'll go back. I got my phone in my
pocket. If someone, you know, I'm not
going to turn anything down, but, you
know, I don't I don't foresee us doing
anything else for the rest of the night.
How well do you sleep on a night like
this when
you've got each of the trenches really
[snorts] addressed and and settled? Very
well. Very well. Yes, good question.
Yeah, just, you know, it's not again,
it's not just yes, like the trenches are
so important, and you know, we're we're
all about, you know, building it from
the inside out, but it's just, you know,
when you when you get the guys that you
love and they happen to play in the
trenches as well,
that's just a little bit added bonus,
but but we'll definitely sleep good at
night. Sleep even better because I
didn't wait till the end of the night to
talk to you guys.
You guys should sleep better. When
you're taking
you know, a high value pick like first
and second round, how important is it to
have, you know, faith and
a familiarity with the programs that
you're having? Cuz you you have taken
guys from Alabama, Georgia, Michigan
in these top
regions of the draft. How important is
that familiarity?
>> I mean, it definitely Yeah, it it
definitely helps. It's it's not the not
the end all, be all. Like look, if
there's a
there's a kid from the small school, you
know, that's just a really really good
football player that he was worth the
value of drafting in the second round or
first round, then we're going to do it.
Now, our our work and our process and
our preparation is not going to change.
Whatever that was, but maybe it's time
to go, but our um
But in terms of our our our vetting and
our work and, you know, our thoroughness
in watching as much film as possible
and, you know, doing all our work on the
front end with, you know, our sources
and the scouts doing the work,
whether they're at, you know, North
Carolina A&T or they're at University of
Georgia, we're we're going to take the
same process, but I do understand, you
know, guys that come out of certain
programs, you just kind of know what
they've been through, and they have a
track record and history of producing
good players. Any other edge rushers
you're looking at?
>> [laughter]
>> Maybe. Maybe, we'll see. We got a lot of
picks tomorrow, so we'll see. Huh?
Something tomorrow for Rod or for What's
What's on the
fashion?
Yeah, wait till I I'm just going to wear
what I what I wear.
>> [laughter]
>> All right, guys, thanks. Appreciate it.